Hammad Ahmed

Principal Software Engineer

Skype: hammad2.7

Email: hammad27@live.com

Portfolio: www.hammadahmed.netlify.app

Lahore, Pakistan

Objective

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Excels in every stage of the life cycle of software development, including design creation, coding, debugging, testing, and maintenance. Expert in devising innovative and tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries. Advanced skills and knowledge of leading programming tools with a strong background in algorithms, and data-processing logic.

Experience

PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER | APR 2020 - PRESENT InnoStark Technologies, Lahore, Pakistan

- Client consultation on application development, project status, and performance-related issues.
- Structuring new or modifying/optimizing existing database objects.
- Implementing new or modifying/optimizing existing applications.
- Providing mentoring services to junior developers as needed.
- Improving system performance by making proactive adjustments and resolving bugs.
- Revised, modularized and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs.
- Orchestrated efficient software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | MAR 2016 - APR 2020 InnoStark Technologies, Lahore, Pakistan

- Client communication/Requirement gathering and analysis.
- > Implementation of new features and maintenance of legacy web applications.
- Migration of legacy web apps to latest frameworks/technologies.

Education

Master of Computer Science | 2013 - 2016 University of Management and Technology, Lahore, Pakistan Major: Computer Science CGPA: 3.77/4.00

- ➤ Rector's List (2nd Semester)
- Dean's List (3rd Semester)
- Dean's List (4th Semester)

ACTIVITIES

- Listening to music
- Exploring new techniques to improve programming skills

LANGUAGES

- Urdu (Native)
- English (Fluent)

Skills

Languages:

C#, JavaScript, SQL, Java, C/C++, TypeScript

Microsoft Technologies:

ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET Web API, Entity Framework, Windows Presentation Foundation, Windows Form, Windows Service

Web Technologies/Frameworks:

React Js, Vue Js, Angular, Angular Js, Knockout Js, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Databases:

MS SQL Server, SQLite

Others:

Git, Redux, Vuex

References

Will gladly furnish personal and professional references on request.